Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (VADP); Records apap304
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1937-2023; 7; 6.49 cubic ft.; 28.0 GB
  - Utah Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - VA Crime Commission, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - VADP "Capital Punishment and Police Safety" Exonerations and Data Sheet, 2022 February 10
  - VADP and Witness to Innocence Event Flyer, 2011 June 11; 2011 May 19
  - VADP Annual Conference Restorative Justice and the Death Penalty, 2005 (Video-tape 29)
  - VADP Awards Luncheon "Remarks by Rachel Sutphin, Recipient of the VADP 2020 Citizen Advocate of the Year Award", 2020 October 24
  - VADP Awards Luncheon "Remarks by Republican State Senater Bill Stanley on repeal of the death penalty in Virginia", 2020 October 24
  - VADP Awards Luncheon "Remarks by Senator Tim Kaine on the Federal Death Penalty", 2020 October 24
  - VADP Awards Luncheon Video Recording, 2020 October 24
  - VADP Banquet Part One, 1999 (Video-tape 30)
  - VADP Banquet Part Two, 1999 (Video-tape 31)
  - VADP Banquet Photos, 1999; 2001 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - VADP Board Meeting Video Recording, 2021 January 9
  - VADP Board of Dirtectors Members and Terms of Service, 2017 April 17; 2017 February 2
  - VADP Board Virtual Victory Toast Video Recording, 2021 February 5
  - VADP Death Penalty Fact Sheet, 2015 February 12
  - VADP Faith Alive Program Agenda, 2017 January 27
  - VADP Faith Community Membership Form, 2015 February 1
  - VADP Interview on Monday Morning QB, 2021 March 29
  - VADP License Plate, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - VADP Member Sign-Up Form, 2011 April 29
  - VADP Organization Membership Form, 2015 March 9
  - VADP Sign Up Sheet, 2015 February 1
  - VADP Sign-ups, Patrick Henry Libertarians in Richmond, Dale Brumfield, 2018 October 2
  - VADP Table Mini Poster, 2012 October 19
  - Valley Virginia, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - VC3 Capital Murder Case Outcomes, 2020 July 16
  - VC3 Capital Murder Case Spreadsheet, 2020 July; 2020 July 15
  - VC3.Org "Virginia Capital Statutory Scheme: Resources", 2016 July 18
  - VCCC Data Chart of Capital Cases since 1978, 2019 November 14
  - The Verdict Op-Ed "Virginia Delivers a Rebuke to Trump's Execution Spree and Points to the End of America's Death Penalty", 2021 February 9; 2021 February 10
  - Victims Families Against the Death Penalty, 1989; 1994-1995; 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Victims Families Reconciliation, 1990; 1997-2000; 2003; Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Video and Audio Recording Release for Washington and Lee University Presentation on Death Penalty Abolition, 2022 January 20; 2022 February 11
  - Virginia Capital Defender Offices and Attorneys, 2018 November 16
  - Virginia Community Criminal Justice Association Vendor Registration, 2019 November; 2019 November 20-2019 November 22
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Draft Statement of Principles, Revised, 2015 May 5
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Draft Statement of Principles, Revised, 2015 May 8
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Draft Statement of Principles, Revised, 2015 May 20
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Draft Statement of Principles, Revised, 2015 June 17
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty Draft Statement of Principles, Revised, 2015 June 25
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty, List of Signatories, 2015 July 23
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty, List of Signatories, 2016 February 1
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty, List of Signatories, 2017 March 31
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty, List of Signatories, 2017 August 16
  - Virginia Conservatives Concerned About the Death Penalty, Signed Statement of Principles, Cliff Maloney, 2017 August 16
  - Virginia Conservatives Draft Statement of Principles, 2015 March 30
  - Virginia Conservatives Oppose the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, List of Signatories, Final, 2018; 2017 December 15
  - Virginia Conservatives Oppose the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, List of Signatories, Final, 2018; 2017 December 20
  - Virginia Conservatives Oppose the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, List of Signatories, Final, 2018; 2018 January 2
  - Virginia Conservatives Oppose the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, List of Signatories, Final, 2018; 2018 January 15
  - Virginia Conservatives Oppose the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, List of Signatories, Final, 2018; 2018 February 1
  - Virginia Conservatives Oppose the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, List of Signatories, Final, 2018; Undated
  - Virginia Conservatives Oppose the Death Penalty for Individuals with Severe Mental Illness, List of Signatories, Final, 2018; Undated
  - Virginia Cure, Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Currents Episode 1002, 2000 (Video-tape 32)
  - Virginia Death Penalty Appeal Process Graphic, 2013 February 11
  - Virginia Death Penalty Mason-Dixon Polling-Strategy, 2019
  - Virginia Death Penalty Poll, The Tarrance Group Memorandum, 2019
  - Virginia Death Penalty Study "Broken Justice" by Steve Benjamin, 2003 November
  - Virginia Death Row Inmates, 2000; 2004 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Virginia Death Sentences, 1994-2012" Graphic, 2013 May 13
  - Virginia Democratic Party, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Virginia Dogwood Article "Virginia's Racist History With the Death Penalty Could Finally End", 2021 January 5; 2021 January 8
  - Virginia Executed, 1991; 1994-1998; 2000-2003; Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Virginia Execution Map by jurisdiction hand-out with data, 2019 March 1; 2019 April 9
  - Virginia Execution Map by jurisdiction hand-out with data, details corrected, version 1, 2019 July 1
  - Virginia Execution Map by jurisdiction hand-out with data, details corrected, version 2, 2019 July 1
  - Virginia Execution Map by jurisdiction, Poster 24 by 18, 1976-2018; 2019 April 5
  - Virginia Execution Map by jurisdiction, Poster 24 by 18 with data details, 1976-2018; 2019 April 5
  - Virginia Execution Protocol and Operating Procedure, 2017 February 7
  - Virginia Execution Table by Local Jurisdiction, Letter Size, Corrected, 1976-2018; 2019 July 1
  - Virginia Execution Table by Local Jurisdiction, Letter Size, Final, 1976-2018; 2019 April 14
  - Virginia Execution Table by Local Jurisdiction, Letter Size, Final, 1976-2018; 2019 June 20
  - Virginia Execution Table by Local Jurisdiction, Letter Size, Final, 1976-2018; 2019 July 1
  - Virginia Execution Table by Local Jurisdiction, Poster 18 by 24, 1976-2018; 2019 March 1
  - Virginia Execution Table by Local Jurisdiction, Poster 18 by 24, 1976-2018; 2019 April 9
  - Virginia Execution Table by Local Jurisdiction, Poster 18 by 24, Revised, 1976-2018; 2019 March 1
  - Virginia Executions and Death Sentences by Year, 1977-2014
  - Virginia Executions by County, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions by County, GIS Tag with Date of Last Execution, 2019 December 1
  - Virginia Executions by County, GIS Tag with Date of Last Execution ONLY, 2019 December 1
  - Virginia Executions by County, Sorted by Date of Last Execution, 2019 December 1
  - Virginia Executions by County, With Date of Last Execution, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions by County, With Date of Last Execution, Corrected, 2019 June 20
  - Virginia Executions by County, With Date of Last Execution, Corrected, 2019 July 1
  - Virginia Executions by County, With Date of Last Execution, Sorted from Oldest to Most Recent, 2019 July 1
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, 2015 April 21
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, 2015 April 21; 2015 May 15
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, Sorted by County, 2015 April 21
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, Sorted by County, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, Sorted by Race of Persons Executed, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, Sorted by Race of Persons Executed, Numbered, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, White Persons Executed, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, White Persons Executed for Killing Nonwhites, 2019 February 18
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty Information Center Data Table, White Persons Executed for Killing Nonwhites, 2019 June 20
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty USA Website, Sorted by County, 1901-1962; 2019 February 28
  - Virginia Executions, Death Penalty USA Website, Spreadsheet, 1901-1962; 2019 February 28
  - Virginia Exonerations Since 1989, National Registry of Exonerations, 2019 November 15
  - Virginia Faith, 1993; 1998; Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Federation of Republican Women Draft Resolution to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2019 March 7
  - Virginia General Assembly Materials, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Virginia General Assembly Materials, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Virginia House of Delegates Floor Session Video Recording, 2021 February 22
  - Virginia Interfaith Center, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Interfaith Center Day for All People of Faith, 2007 (Cd 3)
  - Virginia Interfaith Center for Public Policy "Abolishing the Death Penalty" Presentation for Workshop, 2021 January 19
  - Virginia Lawyer Article "Capital Punishment: A Review of the Proposed Legislative Reform to Virginia's Death Penalty Laws", 2020 October
  - Virginia Lynching Website Screenshot, 1894 June 23; 1891 October 17; 2017 October 10
  - Virginia Lynchings Slide, 1877-1950; 2020 November 20
  - Virginia Mercury Article "All Democrats running for govenor in Virginia say they support ending the death penalty", 2020 December 15; 2021 January 8
  - Virginia Mercury Article "Before lawmakers abolished the death penalty, expert public defenders had quietly defeated it themselves", 2021 March 26; 2021 March 27
  - Virginia Mercury Article "'Do we deserve to kill?' Executing criminals takes something from all of us.", 2021 February 10
  - Virginia Murder and Sexual Assault Exonerations, 1989-2019; 2022 July 19
  - Virginia Murder Exonerations, 1989-2019; 2022 July 19
  - Virginia Penitentiary Aerial View, 2013 February 4
  - Virginia Penitentiary Cell Block, 2013 February 4
  - Virginia Penitentiary Cell Block 2, 2013 February 4
  - Virginia Penitentiary Interior Yard, 2013 February 4
  - Virginia Pilot Online Editorials "Stop the bargains on executions", 2016 March 10
  - Virginia Pilot Op-Ed "Jennifer Butler: Rethink the death penalty in Virginia", 2016 March 26
  - The Virginia-Pilot Online Editorial "Postpone Prieto's execution", 2015 September 30
  - Virginia Politics Pilot Online Article "State officials may be using Ricky Gray execution to bring back electric chair", 2016 February 15
  - Virginia Remarks for the November 19th Eighth Amendment Project Zoom Session for Abolition Movement's Major Donors, 2020 November 19
  - Virginia Right-Left Criminal Justice Reform Group Draft Statement of Purpose, Original, 2015 February 16
  - Virginia Right-Left Criminal Justice Reform Group Draft Statement of Purpose, Revised, 2015 February 23
  - Virginia Right-Left Criminal Justice Reform Group Draft Statement of Purpose, Revised, 2015 March 11
  - Virginia State Meeting of Amnesty International, 2004 (Cd 4)
  - Virginia Women Convention Vendor Table Form, 2018
  - Virginian Pilot Article "Faith, obligation shape work of local capital defender", 2012 March 20; 2018 November 16
  - Virginian Pilot Article "Richard Cizik: An act of compassion for the mentally ill", 2017 January 29; 2017 January 30
  - Virginian Pilot Editorial Online Article "Bending rules for executions perverts justice", 2016 December 19
  - Virginian Pilot Letter to the Editor "Death Penalty story one-sided", 2017 January 29; 2017 January 30
  - Virginian Pilot Online Article "For execution of Ricky Gray, Virginia plans to use drug involved in 3 botches executions elsewhere", 2016 November 29
  - Virginian Pilot Online Article "Religious leaders call on Gov. McAuliffe, lawmakers to reject the death penalty", 2016 April 18; 2016 April 19
  - Virginian Pilot Online Editorial "Stop playing politics over executions", 2016 April 19
  - The Virginian Pilot Op-Ed "Capital punishment endured in Virginia because of Virginians", 2021 February 6
  - The Virginian-Pilot Op-Ed "Virginia should seize this moment to abolish the death penalty", 2020 January 16; 2020 January 18
  - The Virginian Pilot "Opinion: Virginia should seize this moment to abolish the death penalty", 2021 January 16; 2021 January 18
  - The Virginian Pilot "Virginia Senate votes to abolish death penalty after centuries of executions", 2021 February 3; 2021 February 4
  - Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty, "Current State of Virginia Death Penalty Politics", 2015 July 23; 2015 July 27
  - VOP, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Washington DC Death Penalty, 1997; 2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Washington Post Article "The death penalty ended sooner than expected in Virginia - and not soon enough", 2021 March 27
  - The Washington Post Article "Va.'s top pharmacy official questioned legality of plan to special-order execution drugs", 2016 April 15
  - The Washington Post Article "Viginia advocates set to try again on death penalty repeal", 2020 December 30; 2021 January 8
  - The Washington Post Article "Virginia is about to abolish the death penalty. It was a long, surprising road to get there.", 2021 March 23; 2021 March 27
  - The Washington Post Article "Virginia legislature approves plan to buy execution drugs from secret pharmacies", 2016 April 20; 2016 April 21
  - The Washington Post Article "Virginia moves toward banning capital punishment, in a shift for prolific death penalty state", 2021 January 23; 2021 January 24
  - The Washington Post Article "Virginia Supreme Court Decides Not to Change Rules that Withhold Documents from Defense", 2015 December 12; 2016 July 11
  - The Washington Post Article "Virginia's false choice on the death penalty: Barbarism or secrecy", 2016 April 14
  - The Washington Post Digital Op-Ed by Rachel Sutphin "End the death penalty in Virginia" Article, 2019 November 24
  - The Washington Post Letters to the Editor by MES "End state-sanctioned killing", 2017 April 15; 2017 April 17
  - The Washington Post Local Opinions by Paul O'Shea "The time has come to end Virginia's death penalty" Image Version 1, 2020 July 26
  - The Washington Post Local Opinions by Paul O'Shea "The time has come to end Virginia's death penalty" Image Version 2, 2020 July 26
  - The Washington Post Local Opinions by Paul O'Shea "The time has come to end Virginia's death penalty" Image Version 3, 2020 July 26
  - The Washington Post Local Opinions by Paul O'Shea "The time has come to end Virginia's death penalty" PDF Version 1, 2020 July 26
  - The Washington Post Op-Ed "Guest post: How Virginia ended the death penalty", 2021 March 24; 2021 March 27
  - The Washington Post Op-Ed "I prayed Virginia would end the death penalty. It finally did-and gave other states hope.", 2021 February 19; 2021 February 25
  - The Washington Post Op-Ed "Virginia is on the verge of abolishing the death penalty. Other states should follow suit", 2021 January 27
  - The Washington Post Op-Ed "Virginia must prevent wrongful executions", 2021 February 2
  - The Washington Post Op-Ed by Paul O'Shea "The time has come to end Virginia's death penalty" Print Version, 2020 July 24
  - The Washington Post Op-Ed by Paul O'Shea "The time has come to end Virginia's death penalty" Web Version, 2020 July 24
  - The Washington Post Op-Ed by Rachel Sutphin "End the death penalty in Virginia", 2019 November 24
  - The Washington Post Printed Op-Ed by Rachel Sutphin "End the death penalty in Virginia" Article, 2019 November 24
  - The Washington Post Printed Op-Ed by Rachel Sutphin "End the death penalty in Virginia" Image, 2019 November 24
  - The Washington Press Article "Bill to ban death penalty for severely mentally ill clears GOP-controlled Va. Senate", 2019 January 17
  - Watt Espy Winter, 1984-1985 (Video-tape 33)
  - Web Banner, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Week from DPIC, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Weekly C'ville, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - When a Parent Goes to Jail, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Who Gets to Live, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Why Execute the Retarded, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Why the Death Penalty Doesn't Work, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Wiggins v. Smith, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - William Charles Morva Web Summary, 2016 May 13
  - William Morva Clemency Summary, 2017 May 11
  - William Rehnquist, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - William Zeigler, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Williamsburg Yorktown Daily "Virginia is on its way to abolishing the death penalty. Meanwhile, a mother sgares both grief and relief", 2021 February 16
  - Willie Lynch Speech, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Winston Salem Journal Op-Ed "Jack Payden-Travers: Reflections: Ending the death penalty", 2021 April 23; 2021 April 30
  - Women and the Death Penalty, 1995-1998; Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - World Day Against the DP, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - WPFW Radio Interview on Death Penalty Abolition Featuring VADP Director Michael Stone, 2021 March 29
  - WPFW Radio Interview on Death Penalty Thumbnail, 2021 March 29
  - Wrong on Wrongful Executions, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Wrongful Conviction, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Wrongful Conviction Study, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Wrongful Death Sentences, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - WTKR News Article "With more executions than any other state; Virginia could soon abolish the death penalty", 2021 January 27
  - WTVR News Segment on Senate Judiciary Vote for Abolition, 2021 January 18
  - WVTF "Ending the Death Penalty: What Financial Impacts Could Virginia See?", 2021 January 29
  - You Could be Arrested Mid Atlantic Region, Undated (Video-tape 34)
  - Youth Law Center South Dakota State Training School, Undated (Video-tape 35)